Kenan Yildirim

Front End Web Developer, Web Designer, IT Support Specialist, Business and Information Technology Teacher

Chesapeake, VA kenan9492@gmail.com

Dedicated and focused transitioning military staff officer with 13 years active Military Career. Web Development, Web Design, IT Support, Data Analysis, and Project Management experience. Business and Information Technology Teacher. Communication and management skills with independent and teamwork experience. Talented, resourceful and accomplished office manager with programming proficiency. Authorized to work in the US without sponsorship and open to relocation.

EXPERIENCE

2015 – Present	Web Developer, Designer, Programmer and Digital Marketer Self Employed, Chesapeake, VA
2018 – Present	Substitute Teacher Chesapeake Public Schools, Chesapeake, VA
2015 – 2016	Change Management Staff Officer NATO ACT HQ, Norfolk, VA
2003 – 2015	Staff Officer (HR and Information Systems) Turkish Army, Turkey

EDUCATION

2018 – Present Google Front-End Web Developer Nano-degree program

- In Progress
- Grow with Google Developer Scholarship
- Nano-Degree Program

2018 – 2018 Business and Information Technology Teacher Certification Program

- Old Dominion University
- Certification Program

2011 – 2013

International Security Politics

• War College / Turkey

• Master's Degree

2007 – 2008

International Relationship

• Selcuk University

• Master's Degree

1999 – 2003

Management Information Systems

• Army War Academy / Turkey

• Bachelor's Degree

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, AJAX, Angular JS
- WordPress, AWS
- Atom, Bracket, Sublime Text
- MS Visual Studio, XCode
- · Git, GitHub
- Bash Shell, SQL
- Adobe Creative Cloud, Adobe Photoshop
- MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook)
- Mac Office (Pages, Numbers, Keynote)
- Microsoft Project, MS Sway, MS Publisher
- SharePoint
- C#
- Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Bing Web Master, Google Ads, Bing Ads
- Jaaxy SEO Keyword Tool
- Windows, Mac, Linux OS

SOFT SKILLS

- Hardworking and can work quickly & proficiently under tight deadlines
- Ability to stay focused and prioritize a heavy workload while achieving exceptional quality
- Dedication to assigned job and committed to shared vision
- Adaptable, and results oriented with a positive attitude
- Strong written and oral communication skills on online or face to face
- Time management and organizational skills
- Continuously self-developer, learner and problem solver
- Organization, effective communication and research skills
- System Engineering, Data Analysis and Analytic Thinking
- Leadership and team member experience

CERTIFICATES AND COURSES

- Google Front-End Web Developer Nano-degree program
- Google Web Developer Challenge Certificate by Google
- Google Web Designer Certificate by Google
- Data Science Challenge Scholarship Course (Udacity and Bertelsmann)
- Data Scientist's Toolbox Certificate by John Hopkins Uni / Coursera
- Data Science and Machine Learning Essentials Certificate by Microsoft / EDX
- IT Support Professional Course by Google
 - Technical Support Fundamentals Certificate
 - Computer Networking Certificate
 - Operating Systems Certificate
 - System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services Certificate
 - IT Automation Certificate
 - IT Security Certificate
- PRINCE 2 Foundation and Practitioner in Project Management Certificate by Axelos
- Managing Projects Course and Certificate by ESI International
- Introduction to Strategic Communication Course and Certificate by NATO School
- Operations in Information Age Course and Certificate by NATO School
- Cyber Defense Awareness Course and Certificate by NATO School
- Microsoft Office Specialist Certificate by Microsoft
- Microsoft Project 2013 Advanced Course and Certificate by Career Academy
- Swift Fundamentals Certificate / SoloLearn
- SQL Fundamentals Certificate / SoloLearn
- JavaScript Fundamentals Certificate / SoloLearn
- C# Fundamentals Certificate / Microsoft Virtual Academy
- C# Fundamentals Certificate / Udemy
- C# Fundamentals Certificate / SoloLearn

INTERESTS

- Web developing/designing, Content writing, SEO optimization
- Digital marketing, email marketing, social media marketing and affiliate marketing
- Tech savvy, computer and new technology tools / IT Support
- Social Media (Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus, Pinterest, Instagram, LinkedIn)

PERSONAL PORFOLIO

- www.kenanyildirim.us
- https://github.com/Kenan2017
- www.encryptedusbdrives.com
- www.techlifemaster.com
- www.happypregnantwomen.com

- www.dealtuners.com
- www.phonerium.com
- <u>www.vacationtuner.com</u>

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Turkish (Native)